### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ronald-s-s (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Interpersonal Skills Leadership Architecture

## Languages

Indonesian (Native or Bilingual)
English (Professional Working)

### **Publications**

Analysis and Design of Enrollment System Integrated with Enterprise Resource Planning System Microsoft Dynamics AX 4.0

# Ronald Susanto

Highly experienced in IT Business and Digital Solution Delivery at various industries with multi discipline technologies Indonesia

# Summary

Experienced information technology and business process in sales and logistic with a demonstrated history of working in the consumer goods industry. Skilled in Solution Architecture and Delivery, Business Process Analysis and Mapping, with technical skill in SAP, Siebel, Oracle, Java, .NET, and many various technologies. Strong operations professional with a Bachelor of Computer Science from Universitas Bina Nusantara (Binus).

# Experience

Kawan Lama Group Deputy Chief of IT April 2022 - Present (2 years 11 months)

At my role, I am leading various workforces application development and maintenance which consist of about 50 headcounts to deliver software for company operation including custom development, third party integration, cloud platform utilization, and application support. We aim to standardize governance of technology, increase delivery speed by automating many things in the development pipeline, and apply microservice containerization to ensure system high available, scalable, and resilience; by assessing and implementing DevOps tools (Collaboration, CI/CD, APM, Regression Testing, etc) and streamline all technology uses.

PT Sierad Produce, Tbk
Digital Solution Head
February 2020 - July 2022 (2 years 6 months)
Jakarta, Indonesia

The aim of my role is driving, assisting, and helping business users to go through the journey of digital transformation and benefit from it by bring digital solution for them. Working widely end to end from upstream to downstream and its subsidiary companies; from assessment, initiation, managing and driving project, delivering solution, support business, maintaining digital

product and benefit measurement are key points at this job desk. The ultimate goal is to make sure digital adoption is profitable for the company.

Prudential Life Assurance
IT Business Partner & Product Owner
May 2018 - February 2020 (1 year 10 months)

Greater Jakarta Area, Indonesia

- Contact point of business user for any initiatives / enhancement / increment of digital product
- · Maintain good rapport and communication between IT and business users
- Plan roadmap of product / solution for business user in order to meet company goals.
- Drive and prioritize product requirement from user to be developed by development team.
- Compile business case for budget approval and manage budget allocation for the project
- · Manage and drive vendor to deliver the product well
- Collaborate with delivery lead to drive the technical solution for digital product
- Manage and drive squad development team to deliver high value of product / solution
- Manage team to support all incidents / issues of the product
- Maintain a good working environment among the team

#### PT SMART Tbk

IT Business Delivery Manager October 2016 - April 2018 (1 year 7 months) Indonesia

- Collaborate with business process owner and controller to evaluate and identify the bottleneck of current sales and distribution business process.
- Assess, analyze, and validate requirement of system enhancement or change request in sales and distribution process.
- Provide best practice design automation for the business process in the blueprint document.
- Manage development, configuration, and ABAP coordination of SAP sales and distribution module.
- Conduct User Acceptance Testing to validate the system enhancement meet the requirements of the users.
- Provide user training as a part of change management support.
- Coordinate the strategy and manage system implementation / migration of SAP sales and distribution module.

 Review, support, and roll out the SAP and system enhancement on sales and distribution process.

#### PT SMART Tbk

IT Business Partner Manager 2012 - 2016 (4 years)

Key role and responsibilities:

- Reviewing existing business process and find initiatives to improve current business process through system enhancement and automation.
- Gather, clarify, and finalize user requirements.
- Analyze and design the business process improvement from technical perspective.
- Develop system enhancement/automation documentation based on the business process improvement requirements.
- Monitor and evaluate project progress.
- Provide regular updates on enhancement initiatives/projects progress and significant issues.
- Provide training to support team and users.

### Accenture

1 year

CRM Development Lead

2011 - 2012 (1 year)

Client: Indosat - Indonesia

Key role and responsibilities:

- Design solution in Siebel CRM area in order to align with leading practice and requirement of the project
- Provide effort estimation, manage Siebel resources and timeline of development involving risk and quality management
- Server environment maintaining and coordination across multiple streams of development, testing, and fixing support
- Manage Integration interface flow design and agreement between CRM system and other external systems
- Documenting and knowledge sharing to business user and support system team
- Maintain relationship, working environment, and communication among team members, clients, and managements
- Deliver the solution based on schedule and make sure the CRM system deliverables are working correctly as expected

 Support the system, fixing issues, provide recommendation in order to resolve Siebel CRM problem during development, SIT, UAT, and go-live phase

Web Portal Development Lead

2011 - 2011 (less than a year)

Client: Indosat - Indonesia

Key role and responsibilities:

- Create the initial framework and Prove of Concept on features to be used by web portal
- Design framework and technologies implementation, provide effort estimation and schedule of development
- Lead the development team, manage the working environment, and communication between the team members, and managements
- Deliver the solution based on schedule and make sure the system built is working correctly as expected
- Conduct performance test to the web portal to measure and verify volume transaction to be handled
- Support the system, fixing issues, provide recommendation to resolve web portal problem during development, SIT, UAT, and go-live phase

### Accenture

2 years

Siebel CTI Expert

2010 - 2010 (less than a year)

Client: Telekom Malaysia - Malaysia

Key role and responsibilities:

- Translate Functional Design of CTI integration requirement into a technical implementation
- Develop CTI module in Siebel related to TM Call Center enhancement
- Configure Siebel CTI Definition with Avaya Siebel Adapter to integrate Avaya softphone with Siebel CRM System
- Conduct end to end testing and establish connection between Avaya Server,
   Siebel Server, and end user PC in call center
- Transfer knowledge and develop team member to be able to handle CTI module well

Siebel Configurator

2009 - 2010 (1 year)

Client: Indosat - Indonesia

Key role and responsibilities:

- Develop and configure Siebel CRM based on solution architecture given and perform a unit test to verify the result against the functional design
- Develop and implement Siebel EIM process to handle amount of registration data
- Follow Siebel development methodology to develop, track, test, and deploy the items through many environments for development, SIT, UAT, staging, and so on

Java Weblogic Developer 2008 - 2009 (1 year)

Client: Indosat - Indonesia

Key role and responsibilities:

- Develop batch interface to handle a big number of transaction provisioning for prepaid subscriber service in Indosat
- Develop web application UI to handle order and service for prepaid subscribers in Indosat
- Handle integration and enhancement prepaid application with other external systems
- Reverse engineer and enhance production card application using J2EE framework to accommodate new functionality and better performance

TITANS Creative Learning Center Operational Manager 2006 - 2007 (1 year)

This is a partime job while study in Binus University. Before this there are also freelance programmer, coordinator, and instructor there.

# Education

Universitas Bina Nusantara (Binus)
Bachelor of Computer Science, Database · (2004 - 2008)